Okay.
I think we're at starting time.
And I think they have.
We have left it to me
to moderate the session, so.
And I do see a few folks here.
So this is going to be
a little bit.
It is experimental.
I don't know what's going to happen.
It's experimental
on a couple of different levels. One.
This has a lot to do with my creative
project right now and my research,
and they're very much overlapping
and coming from one another
and coming to sort of if you think of it
as like a drawstring, it's
sort of starting to to draw in now,
as I can see
the end be being ever nearer.
So what I'm going to do
is I'm going to give you
a little introduction to the project
and then a little introduction
to this tool
that I want to play with
that is not completely unfamiliar.
If you're familiar
with like Miro and other sort of open,
collaborative spaces like that,
but it is a newer one,
but with fewer features
because it is open source
and freely available and very.
It's a hippie platform, I guess.
So what I'm going to do is
I will share my screen
so that we can see this
so that I can go over the, the,
I guess, the philosophy of the,
the project.
So it's going to look a little messy here
because
this is both the canvas
for the experiment
and the presentation of the background
and that sort of thing.
So bear with me.
So this,
this the notion of hydrogen narrative
and where I'm coming from
will become more obvious here momentarily.
I don't think I started at the beginning.
No I didn't. Sorry.
We're going to scroll
all the way back to the beginning,
because this is
not where it wanted to start.
You would
have thought that I would be prepared,
but no.
All right.
So this is the second slide.
So we started on the first slide.
Yeah.
So we are in as Siobhan notes,
we are in tapestries media.
I have not worked
with this collaboratively before.
So I will note
that there is a duplicate of this in Miro
if we encounter problems with tapestry,
because just because I wanted
to make sure
that we could do something and I will,
you will have the links to that shortly.
I've just given this is the link.
This is just the link to my abstract.
And this is just the abstract from the
this conference.
So if you're here, I'm presuming
that you read something about it or
you really like my random chicken stories.
I don't know.
There may be some chicken stories,
but what I want to introduce
is this speculative research figure
known as the Reveler
and Extragalactic Archivist,
who studies knowledge systems
as expressed through storytelling.
The ruler does not moderate or summarize.
She pulls a thread and records
its connections in the fiber.
So this is a this is the entire premise
of what I'm working on at the moment,
which is,
an intergalactic archivist,
but also researcher, experimenter,
someone who wants to
pull things apart, to look at them
and see how the stories are shaped.
We'll we'll figure that out here
more in a in a second.
So I presented at
this presented this project
not that long ago,
in fact only 16 days ago in Loughborough.
Yep. That's how you pronounce
that Loughborough
at the Weird Modernism Conference.
And so that entire presentation
is indeed here.
And it is in the marrow board as well.
And so I'm going to start
with, just see if I can.
Yeah. So
it's gonna why is it thinking so hard
if we need to pop over to the marrow
to look at it.
It is all in here as a PDF.
It just doesn't want to talk to me
right now.
Okay, let's pop over to the Miro board and
look at it here.
Somewhere.
There it is.
Okay, so this is just
it's a PDF of all the slides.
And I'm not going to spend a lot of time
on each one
because nobody has time for that.
Nobody's interested
that I'm just going to explain.
So the the idea for the Hydra is based
loosely
on Helen seeks use
the laugh of the Medusa.
Right.
The reclaiming of the monstrous in
feminine writing, in writing from those on
the margins who have been historically
marginalized in the literature.
The discourse is mainly about white women,
though when we talk about
feminist literature,
because and my theory on that
is that there's a dominant hegemony,
right?
Which is this is white
European man in Western culture,
and there are barriers erected
and there are circles of.
Access.
Right?
So those in the closest circle
to that inner access would be
white rich women, aristocracy,
that sort of thing.
And so when we start seeing text
and literature emerge
in various Western European languages,
we see white women.
But and for a long time that was all
that was discussed.
So I wanted to move beyond
this notion of just Medusa,
who in the discourse is primarily
involved in that early feminist
literature?
Equity, feminine
mode of discussion
and pull in the hydra
as a an alternative?
The Hydra is a cousin to Medusa, but
instead of having snakes for hair, it is.
There are just many different heads of
serpents, and there's no hierarchy there.
So it works well for me as an idea
for both electronic literature and also
this idea that there is no one group
that's any more privileged than any other
or should be, as it were.
And so that we can talk about
the separate heads and they are separate.
They are not monolithic, and they can be
separate without having to be the same.
And so that was the idea behind that.
So this the
vocalic mixed
experiences, resistant polyphony,
this idea that even
just by writing from the margins,
we are resisting the
hierarchy,
the dominant culture, as it were.
Keep going.
And so, as I've already talked about that
a little bit,
and I really love you'll hear me
talk about this a lot.
Our contact fiction,
which Abigail Directo draws
from Derrida's notion of archives
as ever expanding and never closed.
So direct is talking about fanfiction here
and how we have a base story
and it sort of grows up like,
like a chanty town or a Hoover ville
or desire architecture.
Right?
We're looking for more of what we want
and we're filling in the gaps.
And so this as a tool of social criticism,
mainstream culture or,
or dominant culture did not give me
what I was looking for out of culture.
So I have made something myself
to fill in that gap.
And it is a part of social criticism
to do that, to take part in that.
So where I'm talking about so
this is the definition that I'm working
with, which is narratives
or creative forces that are plural
regenerative sonic
and the Catholic is very important.
I can get into that later, but
that's one of my favorite bits
and irrepressible.
So hydration narratives, hydration
literature works
that multiply, weaving connections
and proliferating under suppression.
The idea that if you cut one head off
to more grow in its place,
reclaiming forms of knowledge
and expression historically demonized
as monstrous, feminine, queer or chaotic.
So again, it's that reclaiming
of the monstrous and going, heck yes!
We're not going to write another hero's
journey story.
We're going to do something different
because our experience is different
and that is valid, and that is important.
And yes,
this is an incredibly broad definition.
It basically arises
because I got really tired of
writing about works by.
People who are historically
marginalized, or listing the
long list of groups, or saying
the global majority, or at least global
majority, is a positive reference.
But I got tired of defining it by
comparison
with the dominant hedge of money,
and by defining it
with what has been done to these groups.
So historically, marginalized means
that something has been done to them.
It's victimizing.
Whereas I, I can talk about these works
that are different,
that are coming from a different
experience, that have been chopped off
over and over and over
and ignored over and over and over,
and we have to rediscover them
every generation.
I wanted this positive
way to talk about them and sort of start
to look at different heads
and have a way to say, okay, this is just
these are parts
of our whole human culture, but
we're not saying that there's
any one fit dominates over another.
So the creative
project, this is a multiform novel.
It's primarily an experiment with Epub.
Can we make hypertext from Epub
that can then go into commercial markets
along, you know, Amazon, whatever, just
just as easily
as any other electronic book.
And to also have it be capable of.
Working as a twine work
obviously a very different work
and print novel.
So there's poly vocab in that.
There's seven main characters
and seven connected stories.
The Seven Sisters I say multilingual,
but it's really mostly just bilingual.
I guess if you count the code
in some places where it will be,
there's
there's some XML type stuff on CSS.
It's definitely resists closure.
That was one thing
I struggled with as I started writing it.
It was that my aim for
it was to be published
and commercial,
and there you sort of struggle
with that expectation of the market.
But the more I started looking into
existing
and literature, the more I realized
that no, closure is not important.
Closure is not something that we do
because we don't necessarily like endings.
We're not sure what's going to happen.
And there might not be this nice, neat,
positive closure for us.
So that was important to me.
And these are content conventions
trying to build on this,
this notion that the story is build on one
another and reference one another
and do different things and centered in
this queer or indigenous or resistance
approach to knowledge,
which is where the reveler comes in.
As as someone who wants to.
It has a different approach to knowledge
than our traditional empirical approach.
So we have this idea that science
is important and Stem is important.
It's what's going to move
the world forward,
and you have to be able to do
the scientific method on things,
and it has to be observable and
objective and testable and repeatable
and all these sorts of things.
Well, that's just one kind of knowledge.
By privileging that as the end
all and be all of knowledge,
we have very much lost,
lost our attention and lost our lost
our way a bit from our
the basic human knowledge,
which is narrative
and communicated based knowledge.
So the
the story is, is
the and I'm going to read you a passage
that this is an example
of what it looks like in an ereader.
At least this is an early version.
It's it's going to be a little bit
more advanced than this.
But there's essentially hypertext
that can take you between the stories,
and you do kind of go through them as,
as though they are woven
into the same text.
And this, this particular passage is
the one that really led me to this idea
of hydration
literature and hydration narratives,
as well as the notion of knowledge,
because I was trying to come up with a way
to frame these stories together.
Like what? Why are we looking at them?
And that's what I came up with,
the idea of the Ravelry.
This is the entire book
is the Ravelry research output.
So she has split a universe into seven
at different points
in the 20th century timeline
in order to see what what happens.
And then she's gone.
Okay, I want to study
a certain set of atoms to see what
the differences are,
because these universes have been split.
So this is a study of atomic memory,
and it is presented
in this hypertext novel format,
because it's the best way to convey
the sort of non empirical knowledge
about how these atoms express themselves
across different universes.
So she says, atoms have memory.
We've observed this memory
for a very long time without knowing
that's what was behind
the strange behavior of these tiny units
of the universe.
The observations recorded here are
the result of one researchers life's work.
The primary method employed is raveling.
Observe the behavioral effects
of atoms across parallel universes
with particular attention
to recurring patterns.
Despite cumulative variances
and continued divergence,
I chose a purely text based medium
for the communication of outcomes,
as opposed to
the more widely used memory download.
Because the art of creation
enables a deeper, more complete connection
to the subject matter, and a novel
seemed in keeping with the era examined.
So this is the Ravel
giving an introduction to her
knowledge communication
in the form of this novel.
So I'm hoping that that helps to.
Contextualize what
we're we're going to play with here today.
And then this, as I've discussed, this
hydrogen knowledge,
that knowledge comes in many forms
and it is important in those many forms.
We're in the UK right now.
We're going through this awful squeeze
on the humanities.
And I know in the US as well.
I read an article yesterday morning
that said we've lost 4000 jobs
in the humanities in universities
in the UK in the last year.
So this is this prioritizing of
of non humanities of non-human
knowledge and really focusing
on these data and quantitative approaches
and Stem as, as the only ones
that are valuable to society,
which I think is a bad
look for us quite frankly.
So yeah,
we have student visa changes here too.
And it was bad, bad news for us.
So so that's that's this.
I mean, it doesn't
it just goes on to work side.
And so everything is, is in here
in this presentation on both versions as
and this is a PDF that eventually
would probably load maybe.
So we're back on the tapestries.
So I'm going to introduce you a little bit
to the basics of tapestries.
If you've worked with Miro,
you'll understand that it's
this sort of expandable scrollable.
You can you can zoom in either using
the plus minus buttons at the bottom,
or you can use gestures, as it were.
If you're not currently clicked on within,
you can use gestures to move it
around, zoom in, zoom out,
that sort of thing.
So but there are a couple of things
that are a little bit different.
You've got your editorial bar over here
and this is all this is all
you get on tapestries.
There's not the endless expansion of tools
and things that there is on marrow.
So you have a text that you can do.
So that gives you a text box like this,
where you can type in and add text,
and you can change the background color
in the text and that sort of thing.
As we're familiar with,
you can put in links,
and this is something I have learned
when you put in a link using this feature
or the
or you link to a word in a text box, it's
going to go to an external site,
even if you link.
So each of these
you can click this share and get the link
to this particular object on the canvas.
But it's going to give you
an external link.
So if you use that for a link
within the text on this canvas,
it will open up a new tab
just to go somewhere else in this canvas.
So these sorts of links are for
and if you're in a text box
you click on the double
A here to get formatting menu.
So this link would also
be this would go external.
Buttons are
what are used for internal transitions.
So this is the add button feature.
And you can add a button
that looks like it'll there's one here.
It looks like this.
And then when you click on it
it gives you options
where you can choose a frame or an object
that you want to go to.
If that button is clicked.
And I'll show that to you
here in a second,
I'll show you the demo of that
more exploration in tapestries.
We'll show you that.
As I said, clicking on this
A gives you your
your font options
such as they are and formatting.
You can add files.
So you've got an import files option here.
You can also drag and drop
just straight into the the screen.
And it will add things as.
That's how I added the PDF
of the presentation that's now working.
You can also record audio or video.
I have not tried that,
but you're welcome to.
You do have fewer options than Miro
or similar commercial platforms,
but it's open source.
It's this is created by
this is a project of the Internet Archive,
who makes the Wayback Machine
and has the Internet Archive library
and has a lot of other archive
based projects,
and they're slowly developing this.
It does have a GitHub repository.
You can self host
an instance of tapestries.
I have not done that yet, but it's it's
something that I'm thinking about
because again, this is open source
and you can play with it.
But right now
this is their hosted version.
So the tasks
hopefully
everyone came to a workshop to do a thing
hopefully is
you're going to get some prompts
you have.
You will have seven.
In keeping
with the title of the workshop.
So review the prompts or you can make
your own or don't do whatever you want.
I don't care.
That's that's it's
not my job to tell you what's right.
And yes, I am going to share the link
in momentarily.
We are getting there.
But I wanted everyone to to listen
to the exercise first, teacher first.
So you're going to add Lexie's nodes
responses to whatever prompts you choose
or your own prompt or what have you.
And I don't care how messy it is,
how wild it is.
This is this is the whole point.
Let it go crazy.
You do have connection arrows.
So you can see on this text box
there are the corners
which are sort of black filled in black.
Those will resize your text box
and then you've got connections
where it says drag to connect.
So you can connect objects together
using these lavender
dots on the frames of each.
What the goal is I would like to see you
linking
to one another's nodes as they emerge.
So there's just one tiny, tiny thing
that I'm asking you to do.
So to have that relational proliferation,
where can you link things together?
You can use AI, you can go prompt AI.
I just want you to
tell us what you've done and why and how,
just to have that openness.
I there's no judgment about using AI.
Use it, don't use it.
I do not care. Embrace the mess.
Be higgledy piggledy, get everything
tangled, screw things up, delete
somebody else's work.
Don't do that.
But just run wild and free.
And if you are struggling
with the interface,
once I give it to you,
I haven't given it to you yet.
Then you can put what you want
in the chat and I will put it on the.
Canvas.
So we're going to try tapestries first
because I it fits better
with the themes and philosophy, but
we will have the marrow board as a backup
if we struggle with this sort of newer,
more unstable piece of tech.
And now some links
which I will put in the chat so you can
click on them directly.
So we will all be working in the tapestry.
And as I say, I have done
a small trial of this on my own.
It works okay,
but if more of us getting on
it makes it crazy,
we can go to the marrow.
So this is
maybe I took the button out.
There is a button here somewhere.
Maybe, maybe maybe.
Yeah, there's a little button here.
Yeah. Which does get started.
And then I'm not in I'm
not in viewer mode.
So if I'm in viewer mode
it will take me to the next place.
So that's how button works.
Now I'm in author mode.
So these are the prompts.
Or as I say, you can make your own.
What would you build if no one watched?
Describe the room
where your ideas are allowed to exist.
Who holds the key?
If your work were unsupervised,
what harm might it do?
What do you know that you cannot publish?
If your discipline were a species,
what would it be evolving toward?
This could be discipline, your practice,
your research, your knowledge.
Whatever your interpretation of discipline
is, your knowledge is a story
who taught you how to tell it,
and the one that I've given
a little sample entry here in is
what have you learned in secret?
And so I talk about the Hydra
as a let's see,
it will come up here if I do it right.
Yeah.
There we go.
The Hydra was a many headed,
femme coated beast whose only wrongdoing
was to not be like the dominant hierarchy
of Greek dudes, and to be immortal
presented a formulaic challenge
to our scripted hero.
And toward that end,
Francis Bacon has quite a lot
to answer for in my philosophy.
So please, I'm going to stop sharing
so that I can see people
and see the chat and respond as people
travel to the interface,
are we able to get on the the tapestry?
Yes. If we click on that link,
I see a thumbs up from Siobhan.
Thumbs up from Jolene.
Excellent thumbs ups.
So go ahead, find your favorite prompt.
Use the.
Text.
Box to add
whatever you want, and I will shut up
so that people can do creative things
on the top of the street.
I will be your reveler today,
and if you tell me you're
you can't figure something out,
or you want to move something somewhere,
or you want to link something somewhere
or something
wild, I will help you do that.
Actually, on
the tapestries, could you share
your screen and show us how to do it?
A text box again,
what I had wanted to do on your prompt
of what can you not publish?
I wanted to say
all the secrets in the world,
but somehow I ended up on a comment.
That's all right.
So if you are here.
Yeah.
So what you're going to want to do is
you've got this text guy over here,
I tried that.
Go for it. Yeah. What did I not do?
It should give you a text box.
And at the moment, my text boxes are so.
There's so hard to see. Okay.
It is if you go click on a initially
and change it to a different background
color, it's a little bit easier.
Oh okay. Yeah.
And then you can just type in there.
I seem to when I created mine
it seemed to have like default links.
Did I do something wrong
or was I maybe looking at someone else
who already created a link?
Which one? Where are you?
Are you down here on extinction?
Oh, I have, hang on.
Let me just see if I can change the color.
And then maybe you can see me.
No, let me just try again.
A whole new one, and I will.
Okay.
I think trouble dragging now.
It can be a little finicky.
Okay.
You'll see a blank canvas.
So it may help if you.
I'm not sure where you entered
if you scroll out,
because it's
sort of one of these infinite canvas
where everything either gets very small
or you can wind up very zoomed
in, where you just have
a blank piece of canvas.
So try zooming out
is what I would recommend.
Does that help?
And now that I have my text box,
I clicked on add link but couldn't
see how to link the two together.
Okay, so if you want to,
you want to connect it to your prompt.
Yeah.
So if you've got you go from the prompt.
From the prompt
has we'll have lavender dots.
Oh so does.
That.
You can drag an arrow.
To your.
Text box.
Or vice versa.
Some of the things are a little bit
counterintuitive initially,
especially if you've worked
with other tools.
It's kind of cool
if anybody if you hit focus,
then you're just looking at your box.
So I think if you're trying to write
something longer or having trouble
seeing, it's a neat feature. Yeah.
So if you look at my screen at the moment,
it's this little box here
on the once you're once
you've selected your text box,
this sort of looks like a little camera.
And you can hit that
and it zooms in on what you're writing,
and then you can hit it
and it goes back to where you were.
Okay.
So you're hitting Firefox.
All right.
Good works in Chrome. Yeah.
Always if you're having something.
Some PDM laughing at your comment.
If you're having problems
in a certain browser,
it's always a good idea
to try a different browser.
I'm in Firefox, but who knows what version
I have, or settings or Mac is different
and etc.
etc. so.
How do I do colored fill in a box?
Miss that.
So see the color fill over here? Okay.
There you go.
Yeah I think I know where it is okay.
Oh no no no sorry.
Oh my god not that background.
So make sure that your box is selected.
Yeah I thought it was okay.
That was me I was never mind.
I'm sorry. I'm still.
Oh I see someone clicked over here.
Yeah.
The little paint palette on the, the
the main menu
is it does change the background color.
Okay.
I thought that would change the background
color the not the background
but my text box color.
And it did not know.
I'm trying to figure out
how to change my text box color.
So your text box color,
if you've got your
your text box selected
and you click on a for format.
No, sorry.
You only want to do that.
I'm so glad.
So you could for format I'm not seeing it.
Oh I might not have it selected. Yeah.
Make sure that your text box is selected.
It will have its little dots
around on the corners
and in the middle of each line.
Okay.
And then you click on the double
A for formatting
and you'll get an option for the text box.
Background color I can't figure
out how to get the text box.
Do you want to share your screen, Dena?
Sure.
Oh, it's not turned on.
That's okay.
Share settings, turn it on.
I believe I'm okay. Cool. Yeah.
Okay. Sorry about that. Okay.
I figured out how to
fill to my color fill, but I have
completely changed the background, and.
All right, I'll change how to do.
See, this is the background
because I get that.
And so what we do is we turn that back.
But before we do, for just a moment,
I'm still trying to get this.
See, I keep losing it. Yeah.
So you got it there. Text.
You maybe scrolled a little bit
too far to the left.
And so you're formatting.
There you go.
Now your little formatting
button will be on the double a.
Oh so click that okay.
Yeah.
So once you're clicked on that
there was a way to change the background.
Just it's a toggle.
So click on the double A
okay.
And now all the way to the right on
that menu you see the next to that there.
Oh there it is.
Background color of your text box
okay.
And then I can also change the color here.
Okay. Great.
So now I don't know how to do this.
I will change the background
back for everybody.
Sorry about that guys.
All good.
And I will I will stop sharing my screen
so you can have it back.
No worries about what I was going to say.
Who are interested in
doing it for teaching.
Deanie already has.
If you go to the main tapestries.
Medea homepage
I think the very first example tapestry
that comes up is Denise class,
where they did their own tapestries,
and then she collected them
into a tapestry
where you can see all of them.
So it's a it's a really good model.
We learned about DNA and I learned about
this at the same event.
Well,
well, can we add images?
Of course.
Yeah. Okay. Perfect.
Okay. Absolutely.
Add whatever you like. Right.
You should be able to
add with the either
just drag and drop the file
if it's on your machine.
Okay.
Or you can use the import files,
which is the very top
icon on the main menu.
I'm really sorry
I can't figure out the internal linking
which should be the easiest thing.
So the only thing.
Or do you just want to do
a connecting arrow?
Yeah. Okay.
So let me I will share my screen again.
Okay.
So if you've got me
oh I see I had to move the whole thing.
So I'm on this this node here.
I'm going to mount a little bit.
So it's these little lavender
dots on the frame.
Oh connect okay
I was looking for a menu.
Yeah. Perfect.
Thank you so much.
That's cool.
It does have its challenges.
One of the things that I learned from.
Working in Miro
so long and working in other graphic
design spaces is there isn't
there's not layer ordering.
So whatever order
that you create the stuff
in, that's the layer it puts it in.
You can't change it.
You can't tell it to come forward
or go backward.
And so what I tend to do is
if I want something in front of something
else, I will just copy
and paste a new version of it
so that it's forward.
They're a little,
little quirks.
It's also hard to move,
but yeah,
yeah, it can be a little finicky.
I do not disagree.
And so like
this is an infinite canvas then. Yes.
I love seeing all the arrows pop up.
Yeah.
You can't rotate the boxes.
There is limited capacity
for graphical design on this.
It's very basic. So.
You can link things together.
You can do buttons,
but you can't rotate the boxes.
This is the only shape
of anything that you get.
So I have played a little bit with the
boxes as shapes as opposed to text boxes.
So I've made some shapes out of the boxes
themselves in different colors.
But it's it's very much a stripped down
compared to things like Miro.
You arrived a little bit
after all the explanation.
If you have any questions, feel free
to just throw them into the chat. Any.
Any.
Difficulties or.
Or just jump in.
I love that now you can't tell the prompts
from what people are writing.
It's just going everywhere.
Well, some of that is because some of us
can't move boxes.
So when you were doing
images, you simply go on to import files.
Yep, you can do it that way.
Yep. This this import files.
Or you can just drag
and drop the file into it.
Yeah I drag to drop and it's easy.
Works fine. Yeah.
So great.
I seem to have locked myself
out of editing my box
because I was in the middle of a sentence,
but now I can't.
Right?
Is your box selected?
I accidentally type myself
into the viewer mode
to there's a
there's a toggle in the bottom right.
Yeah.
Make sure that the bottom right
there's an eyeball and not a pencil.
I'm still trying to figure out
how to move things.
Oh, you have to move the whole bar.
Okay, now I'm
finding out how to make large
quantities of jello.
Excellent.
Is there any way to get the default
to be black text?
Because this is tough, I don't know.
Should it should create.
Pardon?
It should create texts in text boxes
in the color you last used.
It's not.
But okay, cool.
You can also, once you have a text box
set the way that you want it,
and you want all your future text boxes
to be that way, you can select.
You can here I'll share screen.
So if you're on your text box
and you're working on it
and you're back on the Not Formatting
mini menu,
you go to the the three dots
that say more and you can make a copy
and it
will just copy the exact same thing.
So if you've already set your text
to be black,
then you can use it that way.
Thank you.
Yes, command.
Command V somehow obscured the entire
thing.
How do you of it though?
Right is problem
was that I had accidentally toggled
out of author mode so you could actually,
like just hit a button.
And yeah, I think there are shortcut keys
that they don't quite
tell you about.
Excellent fun.
I've been a few of those.
Animation.
Excellent. The moon.
That's not if you control.
Plus it gives you deeper lower I see.
I see tentacles.
Maybe for the recording
could you share your screen
and move around the.
Oh yes. Yeah. Good plan,
good plan.
Entire thing somewhere.
Zoom to fit is not a good idea.
Oh, yeah.
You wind up seeing the whole canvas.
So that's for the recording purpose.
Zoom to fit.
Then you scroll way out
because I separated the how to stuff
from the creative space
so that we would have
plenty of room.
I seriously have lost the piece
that I was writing.
I can't find it on the canvas.
Is there any way to identify,
like the pieces you were working on
and just isolate them visually?
That I don't think so.
You know what color it was?
I was just white with black writing.
White with black writing. So.
And it was it was going to be connecting
to the somebodies
about the grandmother. And
yeah, it's like all of a sudden
the canvas went like super huge
and then it has disappeared.
Okay.
Yeah. And.
That to it either.
Let me see if
I'll see if I can't
on the page.
No, no it's just gone too bad.
So I see,
see a few, I can see extinction.
I can see the edges of what I know
and do not know. No.
It was a story
about my grandmother on the comet.
So I think it's gone.
But it's kind of weird.
It means that collectively, like
somebody else was able to do something
that knocked mine out
because of where I was editing.
Yeah.
And how do you select, like a box?
You just click on it.
But some people are putting white boxes on
that are covering up other,
which is a fun
sort of like obscurity question.
Some people are probably doing that
because we have no idea
what the hell we're doing.
I bet if we change the background,
I'll just change the background color
and see if it reveals any hidden boxes.
Some of them are transparent,
some of them are just white.
There's.
Zooming out and see if boxes,
because there's a green box
all the way over here.
There is?
Yeah.
Mine would have been underneath
kind of around where that orange is
when I was a little girl.
So that's the link
that I was making there.
Okay.
But it looks like yeah, it's really gone.
That's. I don't love that.
But this.
Disappear like three times
before I managed to get one stick.
And I don't know why it disappeared.
And I don't know why it eventually stuck.
I wonder if there's a.
Thinking, if it's a sinking thing,
where
when the interface sinks so that we're all
working on the same live document.
It's a version issue.
I'm still having the basic
moving thing issue,
so I can't really make any more.
I'm still I still can't figure out
how to select a box.
Well, if there are
so Dina to select a box.
Show me like
I was trying for that purple one
next to the headless servants.
I wanted to move it out of the way
and I was trying to type in there.
Okay. Big one.
And I wanted to make it smaller, so.
This one.
Yeah. That one.
So if we want to
sometimes it's a click and
I have no idea.
It's smaller. Yeah
I would love to just move the damn box
that I'm in.
Or someone could just make me a box
that exists way off the page.
All right, I will make one for you.
I cannot I cannot drag this.
I cannot I can make it giant,
I guess, like, I can just, like,
make it this giant lumping thing that is
just moving, but it doesn't move as a box.
I'm having the same issues
and interesting.
You have to.
Ave. Okay, so Caitlin,
can you see my green box
all the way to the left
of the mass of texts?
Yeah, I can see that now.
Can you see that I'm trying to make one
that's just underneath the purple.
It's near the orange, so not here.
I'll move it like over to where you are.
So let me just see.
So when I'm here.
But I maybe I'm
not an author mode anymore.
Like, I can't, I can't write anything
inside of it anymore.
I think that was my problem.
Caitlin was I couldn't write
because I wasn't an author mode.
Now I've lost the magic button.
No, no, now I'm in viewer mode.
Now I'm in author mode.
But I still can't write anything
inside the box.
So I think it's Gremlins.
So. Yeah, it should often
be sort of a one and then two click. So.
If you got the box selected
and it says add your text here
and you don't have a cursor, you
click on it again and you get a cursor.
It doesn't even say add your text here.
You want to share your screen.
Caitlin I can see.
Yeah, sure.
What's going on?
Sorry.
It was kind of working before, but
and now of course, the sharing
is right over
top of where I wanted to show you
some stuff.
Yeah.
So here I'm in this box and
I've just created the box.
I could try to create a new box,
but it's kind of the same thing
when I come here.
I don't it doesn't say start here.
So click on the double A.
And then next all the way
down between the A and the left justify.
Click on that closed circle
and give yourself
a different background color
so you can see your text boxes
whatever color you want okay okay.
So now click yeah.
That's because your text is now.
So maybe it was just because it's
white on white. Yeah.
Yeah okay.
So now if you click in there again
you should get a cursor
that you can type with. And you can.
Although that would make sense.
But now I seem to be frozen. Hang on.
Am I in author mode.
No. Now I'm in.
So doing that you're in viewer mode now.
Now I'm in viewer mode.
Okay, now an author mode.
And so click on that okay.
Let me click on focus. There you go. Yep.
Now you got a cursor.
Thank you.
All right I can I can type.
All right. Thank you.
I'll share again for the
purposes of recording.
I'm having so much fun
just finding everybody's
untapped in text boxes and revealing them.
It's like having Dena.
It's like having Jane spaces.
Well, okay,
the exact same thing happened again.
I'm in the middle of writing
and my whole text box disappeared.
I'm not going to write anything more
because it's frustrating.
Like I was just
in the middle of my little red box.
I was in the middle of typing
and it just got blasted away from me.
If you want to
a, you can go over to the mural board
and add whatever you want to add,
or you can type it into the chat of the.
I see some folks have at least someone
has played with the mirror board already,
which is cool.
Or you can type
whatever you like into the chat
and I can put it in for you.
It's curious though,
and it's also a frustrating kind.
I yeah, of interfaces
that delete things but.
But yeah it's I haven't.
This is this is definitely the first time
that I've tried this
with a lot of people working on it.
And I do think it's a version control
like I think
I think it's on a refresh rate that
maybe that
if you be the middle of something.
Yeah, yeah.
Excellent.
And what I'm going to do
is I'm going to leave it.
This will remain live
and it will remain something
that anyone can go in and add to.
It's not public at the moment.
I will make it public.
And what happens is when it's public,
anyone on tapestries can have a look at it
and do things.
So this will be
it will exist, it will
continue to exist and continue to
grow new heads.
And this associative manner is my hope.
Yeah.
I'm not sure if it's a local refresh.
I did notice when I was testing it
and signed in in two different places
that like you could like with Miro,
if you're signed in two different places,
it's pretty smooth.
I think it might be a server side.
Oh, totally.
And other
people are having a lot of success,
so it could just be that maybe I think
they're taking too long or I had some.
Anyway, doesn't matter.
I think for me, if I click on the text box
the wrong way,
then it engages the hotkeys like the eye
for dropping in something or the
oh for opening or the like.
The backspace key deleted my thing
and that's just from touching my
like keypad the wrong way.
So maybe I've just I the way I type,
I accidentally make the erasing thing
happen as part of my maybe I know
we don't have, which is challenging to me.
We don't have a lot of time left.
I'm not sure when the Sims, but before,
could you talk a little bit
about tapestries itself and how it relates
to your idea of the seven
hi Hydra heads,
the intertwining, interlocked
but not hierarchical stories,
and how the medium morphs the message?
In other words.
Yeah, yeah.
So the the stories.
So this this creative piece originally was
and still is an experiment
in publishing for me.
The research wasn't initially
about the stories themselves.
I wanted to see if I could do some elit
with epub
and I obviously you can do it with Epub.
Many people have,
but I wanted to see if we could start to
as not just these sort of standalone
experimental things as like
this will work in a,
you know, a clear market
and you don't have to like be weird
about it because the existing
interactive
texts, which are largely of the choose
your own adventure type,
which is you get to the end of this page.
If you want to go left, go to page 30,
or if you want to go right, go here.
So they you can use
internal hyperlinks for that.
But there are some
some downsides to that,
which is that you have to rely on people
not to just turn a page,
which of course
you have to do in print books anyway.
But the, the, the e-readers
in the book formats really want you to
just turn a page and keep turning a page.
And so putting in hyperlinks
means that you're sort of
defying the conventions a little bit,
and it can be a little bit hard to do.
So. So yeah.
So I just wanted to explore with that
and do something that wasn't, you know,
an electronic reproduction of what we do
in print
with the chooser and adventure stuff.
And so
I frequently
most of what I write a speculative science
fiction fantasy stuff.
And so I have been obsessed
since I was a kid
with the idea of parallel universes and
parallel worlds theory
and quantum entanglements, et cetera, etc.
and you can see some quantum entanglement,
I think, on the screen at the moment.
And so I thought, you know what,
if we look at the same character
across seven different story worlds
that have different timelines, so one key
event, one small key event gets changed
and we can identify that.
And if that thing changes,
how does it make for a different world
that she's living in now.
So it's the same character now, but
historically it's in parallel universe.
Caitlin's textbook stories were also,
I agree, they were they were brilliant.
And so
and the story worlds range from,
you know, realistically utopic
for the fact that all these histories
were changed in the 20th and 21st century.
So we don't go back to the Stone age
to change history.
It only goes back the first.
The oldest timeline change is
World War one.
Well, yeah, World War one.
So going forward from there.
And so it just,
you know, it was seven sisters
and that meant something to me.
And it's linked to the Seven Sisters,
the Pleiades star cluster.
And as I as
I noted, as I went into it
and needed that frame narrative
to pull everything together, like,
why are these seven different stories?
Like, what is this? How did this happen?
It took me a while to come up
with the Reveler with the frame story,
but it was because I was really immersed
a lot more in women made media,
films, books,
reading, elit, all this sort of stuff.
I really made a dedicated effort
and I was noticing
some key differences in that media from
the stuff that we just, you know,
that we just get inundated with
that is quote unquote, the norm,
you know, canonical stuff.
And from there it was
I had that interest in knowledge.
How was our knowledge different
and how do we express it differently
through narrative.
And so that then led me to six,
you and Medusa and bringing it together.
And then tapestries just was a similar.
Philosophy.
And there's no hierarchy.
There's no one way to do it.
There's no necessarily
even a starting point.
You can just kind of go everywhere.
And that's what I like about Miro boards.
But Miro, I used to use,
like precis.
And I will use these new tools
as they come out and get very excited.
But the more popular they get,
the more commercialized they get, the more
they shut down, the more they're there
for marketing and presentation.
So Miro has slowly started moving toward
it being very business
oriented and presentation and marketing
and that sort of thing.
Whereas tapestries,
being with the Internet Archive
as a project, it's open source
and it's more a part of that free and open
collaborative creative space online
that I was interested in.
And I'm going to put on my moderator
hat now
because we are out of time.
So I will stop sharing.
I just want to.
The Christine
I see there's a question about the
it doesn't publish anything.
It is its own thing.
So this is just a creative space.
And as I follow Anastasia's guide
and use Claude
to create my own website,
I will embed it somewhere.
But thank you all so much for coming
and for participating.
I wasn't sure
if this was going to come off, so yay
experimentation and thank you all
so much for for having a play.